Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): He told me he was going to do what he had to do. And when I got in contact with the director, man, he was not only supportive,
he was
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): active. He was quick to response. He did not go past me. He acknowledged me. Acknowledging me. Acknowledgement means so much. He could have taken this the wrong way. Understand that this could have gone
either way.
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): This was happening. They decided to join me.
It's
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): my constitutional right to do this. They didn't have to be a part of
this. Good evening,
Speaker 2: everybody. First, I just want to start by thanking Matthew.
Speaker 3: Whoo!
What Matthew did
Speaker 4: here tonight was not only bring
Speaker 5: together a community, but he brought together a community and its police department.
Speaker 6: Those two components
are in every
Speaker 6: municipality in the country. You have police and you have citizens.
Speaker 7 (lower-pitched voice): One cannot function without the other. And over 200 years ago...
Speaker 8: Would you like to use this? Let's speak right into
it. They
Speaker 8: know how to use those.
Speaker 8: I
Speaker 9: wanted to thank Matthew for bringing everyone together as a community.
Speaker 10: For having
the courage to do
Speaker 12: something like this, and bring together not just a community, but bring together a community and its police department together.
What happened in
Speaker 11: Minneapolis, Minnesota,
Speaker 11: was a disgrace not only to that police department but to the law enforcement profession as a whole. It was an embarrassment for all of the hard-working, trusting men and women that put badges on for the community every
day. In
Speaker 11: this police department, our mayor, Michael Venezia, and me,
Speaker 11: and our command staff instill in our officers every single day that everyone you encounter, no matter what the situation is, you treat everyone with dignity and you treat everyone with
Speaker 7 (lower-pitched voice): respect. Treat everyone as if you were dealing with a family member, as if you would want your mother dealt with, your father dealt with, your brother, your sister, your wife, no matter
Speaker 13: what
the situation is.
What I will
Speaker 14: pledge to you as the director of this police department is that if any one of my officers
Speaker 11: ever did even a fraction of what happened in Minneapolis and acted unproperly during an arrest, a motor vehicle stop, or any encounter, the discipline would be swift
Speaker 15: and harsh.
Over the past
Speaker 16: five years, we've put together community building programs that are unprecedented in this area.
Speaker 17: Our Junior Youth Academy for the last four years, I don't know if there's any kids that are here right now that have attended it in the summer, from the middle school or the high school. But these things like this, our Community Police Academy, our Senior Police Academy, all programs that are built on bringing the police and the community together.
Speaker 17: Not only meeting us and knowing what we do, but building relationships that last, not just for that time period, but relationships that last a lifetime and pass down to generations to keep the community and the police as one.
Okay, so
Speaker 18: he's asking me
Speaker 20: about...
A
Speaker 19: Vice documentary that was done about a year and a half or two years ago and
Speaker 11: how I would respond to it. Well, I responded to it numerous times. The mayor and I held open town hall meetings where the police department was basically set up to look bad based on skewed data.
Speaker 11: And when we brought the proper data forward, and we are the only police department that tracks the racial data of every motor vehicle stop that our police officers can do in this
county. Now I'm going to be quick
Speaker 11: because there's a lot of people that want to talk, but I just want to tell you the most important thing I feel what that does for us. It identifies problematic officers early. Not
Speaker 21: after an incident like this happens, but
before it happens.
If we have
Speaker 22 (higher-pitched voice): an officer that's stopping an inordinate amount of a certain race, of African Americans, of Hispanics, of whites, whatever it may be, it identifies that for us in real time and lets us nip the problem in the bud, correct it, or eliminate the officer.
Speaker 22 (higher-pitched voice): to give the mic back to Matthew. I just want to say thank you. Thank you for coming out and showing your support for this worthy cause, because it's as worthy to us as it is to you. And thank
Speaker 23: you for doing it the right way.
No
Speaker 24: justice, no peace, no
justice, no
Speaker 26: peace, George
Speaker 27: Floyd, Breonna Taylor,
Speaker 28: Breonna Taylor. I got to say, I got to say, like I'm proud. Like
Speaker 29: proud of my town,
Speaker 30: proud
of the people that have
Speaker 31: been around.